Steps for Calculating a Performance Baseline
Hello, Mike Harry. Welcome back where we’re again looking at establishing baselines.
We’re going to start with an example.
Now, let's consider a baseline. Step one. What does it take to do that?
The very first thing that we've gotta do is determine the error rate.
Now, what do we mean by an error? Well, let’s look at some examples.
I think we're pretty clear at that, but this will help. We’ll look at some commercial industrial.
Take banking, for example, or anywhere where people are waited on, a service.
We see these people come and go, coming up to the desks, there to be waited on.
Now, what can an error be? Well, an error could be that this individual right here,
when the customer come up, pulled up the wrong account.
Had to put it away and get the right account. That could be an error.
Now let's consider another one, simple airbag.
We see in airbag there deploying. Well, what might an error be?
Pretty simple, if it doesn't deploy.
Let's look again, at a facility.
As we look at an industrial facility here. We’re going to zoom into the back dock.
And what could an error be? An error could be a wrong delivery.
Pretty simple. The truck pulls up and unloads the wrong materials.
Now again, take something as simple as jumping.
A person makes a jump.
What can an error be? Well, pretty simple.
They stumble and fall. That could be an error.
Now what we’re going to do, is take and divide that error rate
by the number of units produced.
Thereby creating
a unit error rate. Now remember, a unit can be anything.
A unit could be a software program.
A unit could be in the case of jumping, an event.
A unit, in terms of delivery, could be the total order.
A unit can be anything that we want it to be.
Especially, when we're baselining. So, we’re looking at the error rate per unit,
or what we call the unit error rate.
Now step number two. Pretty straightforward.
We take the unit error rate and we divide by the number of opportunities
to get the opportunity error rate.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.